huffingtonpost.co.za 2018-10-10

# The Huffington Post South Africa Privacy Policy

[**The Huffington Post South Africa**](http://www.huffingtonpost.com/) **Privacy Policy**

The Huffington Post South Africa ("Huffington Post", "we", "us" and "our") takes your privacy very seriously. This privacy policy is intended to inform you about the information that is collected from you when you visit the Huffington Post South Africa sites and applications (the "Site"); how this information may be used and disclosed; how you can control the use and disclosure of your information; and how your information is protected. If you use Huffington Post mobile applications or sites, [additional terms apply](http://www.huffingtonpost.co.za/p/mobile-south-africa-tos). If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact our privacy team at [privacy@huffingtonpost.com](mailto:privacy@huffingtonpost.com).

**Consent**

**BY AGREEING TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU PROVIDE US WITH YOUR EXPRESS CONSENT AND AGREEMENT THAT WE MAY COLLECT, GET, RECEIVE, RECORD, ORGANISE, COLLATE, STORE, UPDATE, CHANGE, RETRIEVE, READ, PROCESS, USE AND SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN THE WAYS SET OUT IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY.   WHEN WE DO ONE OR MORE OF THESE ACTIONS WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, WE ARE "PROCESSING" YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.**

**IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THIS, OR ARE CONCERNED ABOUT ANY ASPECT AS IT RELATES TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION, PLEASE DO NOT CONTINUE TO USE THE SITE** **.**

**The above section has important legal consequences for you.   In this section, you expressly give your permission to us to collect, collate, process, share and use your personal information in the manner and for the purposes set out in this privacy policy.  By doing this, you know and accept that you are giving up certain parts of your right to privacy.**

**You will not be able to take any action against us for using your personal information in the way that you have given us permission, even if you suffer loss or damage.**

**1\. Scope**

This privacy policy applies only to the Site. This policy does not apply to information collected through any other website or to the practices of companies that the Huffington Post does not control. Please note that the Site may contain links to other websites. For example, if you click on an advertisement on the Site and link to another website, then this privacy policy will not apply to any information collected on that website. **WE ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PRIVACY PRACTICES OF OTHER WEBSITES, AND WE RECOMMEND THAT YOU READ THE PRIVACY POLICIES OF EACH WEBSITE THAT YOU VISIT.**

**Section 1 has important legal consequences for you.   It:**

  * **excludes or limits Huffington Post's legal responsibilities;**
  * **limits or excludes any rights you have against Huffington Post; and**
  * **places legal responsibilities and liabilities and risks on you.**

**Huffington Post is not liable if you suffer losses or damages when visiting another third party website by following a link to that web site from the Site.   You accept that there may be risks when you use such third party websites, and you do so at your own risk.**

**2\. What information the Site collects**

**Information you provide directly to us:**

You are not required to provide information directly to us in order to view the Site. However, when you use certain Site functions, such as when you register for certain services, access certain content or features, or directly contact the Site, we may ask you to provide information, including:

  * contact information, such as name, email address, postal address, phone number, and mobile number;
  * username and password;
  * information posted in community discussions and other interactive online features;
  * search queries conducted on the Site; and
  * correspondence you send to us.

**Section 2 has important legal consequences for you.   In this section, you agree and accept that there is certain information you must provide to us if you want to enjoy all of the features and functionality on the Site.**

**If you decide not to provide us with such information, you agree that we may limit certain features and functionality on the Site.   You will not be able to take any action against us if you suffer losses or damages in these circumstances.**

**Information automatically collected when you visit and interact with the Site:**

When you visit and interact with the Site, certain information may be collected automatically, including:

  * your computer's Internet Protocol (IP) address;
  * your browser type and operating system;
  * the web pages you were visiting immediately before and after you came to the Site;
  * activities within community discussions;
  * web pages and advertisements that you view, and links that you click on, within the Site;
  * your bandwidth speed and information about the software programs that are installed on your computer;
  * aggregated data about email click-through rates and user video viewing;
  * standard server log information; and
  * information collected through HTML cookies, Flash cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies. For more information, please see our discussion of [cookies and other technologies](http://www.huffingtonpost.co.za/p/cookie-information).

**Information we collect from other sources:**

We may access information about you from third-party sources and platforms (such as social networking sites, databases, online marketing firms, and ad targeting firms), including:

  * if you access third-party social networking services (such as Facebook Connect or Twitter) through the Site, your username and connection lists for those services;
  * demographic data, such as age range, gender, and interests;
  * advertisement interaction and viewing data, such as ad click-through rates and information about how many times you viewed a particular ad; and
  * unique identifiers, including mobile device identification numbers, that can identify the physical location of such devices in accordance with applicable law.

  * Please note that the Site may combine the information that we collect with information we obtain from third-party sources.

**3\. How we use the information that we collect**

**Email Communications:**

We may use the information that we collect to send you e-mail communications, such as editorial updates, information about your account or changes to the Site, and promotional messages about our own or our marketing partners' products and services. If you signed up for one of our email newsletters, we also will send you the newsletter that you requested.

**Mobile Communications:**

With your consent, we may use your mobile number to send you promotions, notifications, or other services.

**Advertising:**

In order to provide our readers with free access to our content, we display advertisements on the Site, many of which are targeted based on information about you. For example, using information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other sources, we may use demographic data or information about your online activities or interests to display targeted advertising that may be relevant to your preferences. Through this process, advertisers reach Site visitors who are most interested in their products, and you see advertising for products or services in which you may be interested. For more information on how cookies and other technologies work, please see our discussion of [Cookies and Other Technologies](http://www.huffingtonpost.co.za/p/cookie-information).

Some of the advertisements you see on the Site are selected and delivered by third parties, such as ad networks, advertising agencies, advertisers, and audience segment providers. These third parties may collect information about you and your online activities, either on the Site or on other websites, through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies in an effort to understand your interests and deliver to you advertisements that are tailored to your interests.

**PLEASE REMEMBER THAT THE HUFFINGTON POST DOES NOT HAVE ACCESS TO, OR CONTROL OVER, THE INFORMATION THESE THIRD PARTIES MAY COLLECT. THE INFORMATION PRACTICES OF THESE THIRD PARTIES ARE NOT COVERED BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY.**

**The above paragraph has important legal consequences for you.   It:**

  * **excludes or limits Huffington Post's legal responsibilities;**
  * **limits or excludes any rights you have against Huffington Post; and**
  * **places legal responsibilities and liabilities and risks on you.**

**Huffington Post is not liable for processing of personal information by third parties arising from third party advertising. You accept that there may be risks arising from such processing, and you accept these at your own risk.**

These third parties may offer you a way to choose not to have your information used for advertising purposes. For example, some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Initiative (EDAA), which provide a single location where you can opt out of receiving targeted ads from member companies. To opt out, please visit the NAI's website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> and the EDAA's website at <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>. For more information about disabling cookies completely, please visit the "[Your choices](http://www.huffingtonpost.com/privacy/index.html#your-choices)" section of the privacy policy.

Please note that if you choose to opt out of having your information used to deliver advertisements tailored to your interests, you will continue to see advertisements on the Site, but these advertisements may not be as relevant to you.

**User Accounts:**

To provide you with an open, but also civil, discussion forum, we track user involvement in our community discussions. For example, we keep track of the ratio of how many flagged comments are eventually deleted in order to award badges to our most effective comment moderators. For more information on this process, please see our [FAQ section](http://www.huffingtonpost.co.za/p/huffpost-south-africa-faqs) about comment moderation guidelines.

**Request Fulfillment:**

We may use the information that we collect to fulfill your requests for products, services, and information. For example, we may use your contact information to respond to your customer service requests or to enable you to participate in features on the Site such as surveys, polls, sweepstakes, and message boards.

**Statistical Analysis:**

In order to learn more about how our Site is used, we aggregate and analyze the data that we collect. We may use this information, for example, to monitor and analyze use of the Site, to increase our Site's functionality, and to better tailor our content and design to suit our visitors' needs.

**Enforcement:**

We may use the information that we collect to prevent illegal activities, to enforce the Site's [Terms of Service](http://www.huffingtonpost.co.za/p/huffpost-south-africa-terms), and to otherwise protect our rights and the rights of our users.

In addition to the uses identified above, we may use the information that we collect for any other purposes disclosed to you at the time we collect your information or pursuant to your consent.

**4\. Information sharing**

The Huffington Post values your privacy, and shares information about our users only under certain circumstances. We will make information about you available to other companies, applications, or people in the circumstances listed below:

  * We may share aggregated information or information that does not directly identify you with third parties to help us develop content, services, and advertising that we hope you will find of interest. Please note that we do not share contact information with third parties that advertise on the Site.
  * We may employ third parties to perform Site-related services, including database management, maintenance services, analytics, marketing, data processing, and email and text message distribution. These third parties have access to your information only to perform these tasks on our behalf.
  * If you choose to engage in public activities on the site, such as posting comments on community message boards, any information you submit can be read, collected, or used by others. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information in public activities or submissions.
  * We may share information about you in the event that the Site is acquired by or merged with another company or a similar corporate transaction takes place. However, the Site will notify you by placing a prominent notice on our site or sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your account before your information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.
  * We may share information about you to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety or other rights and interests of any person, violations of the Site's Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law.
  * We may share information about you to respond to subpoenas, search warrants, judicial proceedings, court orders, legal process, or other law enforcement measures, to establish or exercise our legal rights, or to defend against legal claims.
  * In addition to the scenarios identified above, we may share information about you for any other purposes disclosed to you at the time we collect your information or pursuant to your consent.

Please note that third parties may independently collect data about you, including your IP address and information about the websites you visit and the links you click, through cookies, clicks on links, or other means when you visit or view ads on the Site. For more information, see our section on [cookies and other technologies](http://www.huffingtonpost.co.za/p/cookie-information) and the Third-party services section below.

**5\. Third-party services**

To customize your experience on the Site and to simplify the Site's registration process, we provide you with the opportunity to access or interact with third-party services, such as Facebook and Twitter. When you connect to the Site through these third-party services, we may share information about you with these third-party service providers and they may share data about you with us.

When you allow us to access your data through a third-party service to create a Site profile, we may use this data for several purposes, including:

  * _Creating relationships automatically within our system_. For example, if you connect to us via a service with a public friend list, like Twitter, we may check to see if any people you follow on Twitter are also Site members. If we find a match, we will replicate your Twitter relationship with those members, setting them to be fans, followers, or friends on our Site.
  * _Suggesting relationships_. For example, if you connect via a service that has a private contact list (like Google and Yahoo!), we check for people in your contacts who are Site members and suggest that you become a fan of these users. This process is not automatic; you must affirmatively choose to become a fan of these suggested users.
  * _Populating a list of potential friends to whom you can send emails_. When users share content with their friends using, for example, the forward-to-a-friend feature on the Site, we may use friend lists from third-party services to create a list of contacts to whom you may choose to send the email message.
  * _Populating a list of potential friends to whom you can send service-specific messages_. For example, we may use friend lists from a third-party service to create a list of contacts to whom you may choose to send an invitation to view an interactive slideshow.
  * _To enhance and personalize your experience on the Site_. When you are connected via a third-party service, we may access certain account information, such as your profile picture, what stories are popular in your network, and what your friends are saying about certain articles or blog posts, in order to enhance and personalize your experience on the Site.

In addition, if you connect to a Facebook account, your experience on the Site may be personalized. For example, you may automatically see what stories are popular in your network, and what your friends are saying about particular stories.

Please note that you may disconnect third party accounts at any time. [Click here](http://www.huffingtonpost.com/users/social-preferences/) for a link to your social profile, where you may set your privacy preferences or disconnect all of your third-party service accounts. You also may be able to modify your privacy settings directly with the third-party service. To modify your Facebook privacy settings, [click here](http://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=privacy). To modify your Twitter privacy settings, [click here](https://twitter.com/account/settings).

**PLEASE REMEMBER THAT WE DO NOT CONTROL THE PRIVACY PRACTICES OF THESE THIRD-PARTY SERVICES. WE ENCOURAGE YOU TO READ THE PRIVACY POLICIES AND TERMS OF USE OF ALL THIRD-PARTY SERVICE PROVIDERS.**

**Section 5 has important legal consequences for you.   It:**

  * **excludes or limits Huffington Post's legal responsibilities;**
  * **limits or excludes any rights you have against Huffington Post; and**
  * **places legal responsibilities and liabilities and risks on you.**

**Huffington Post is not liable if you suffer losses or damages when visiting another third party website by following a link to that web site from the Site.   You accept that there may be risks when you use such third party websites, and you do so at your own risk.**

**6\. Your choices**

**Deactivating your account**

You can deactivate your account at any time by visiting the preferences page for your profile. When you deactivate your account, your user profile will be disabled, but your public comments will remain on the site. The Site has no responsibility to take down, remove, or edit any of your public activities or any submissions that are a result of your public activities. For more information, please review our Terms of Service.

**Cookies and other technologies**

As discussed in the sections on [cookies and other technologies](http://www.huffingtonpost.co.za/p/cookie-information), some information is collected about you automatically through cookies and other technologies, and you consent to the processing of such information as set out below and in the linked sections.

  * . You can change your browser settings to reject all cookies, accept only certain cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. Please note that you may need to renew these settings if you delete your cookies after these preferences are made. These settings also may not apply if you are using a different computer or Internet browser. In addition, many third-party advertising networks are members of the NAI or EDAA. To opt out of having information collected by NAI and EDAA member companies used for behavioral advertising, to obtain information about the technologies these ad networks might use, and to view information regarding their privacy policies, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> and <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>.
  * _Flash Cookies_. You can control how Flash cookies are used by visiting the [Adobe Macromedia site](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). Adobe enables you to allow some Flash cookies from certain websites, limit Flash cookies' storage capacity, and disallow Flash cookies altogether. In addition, if you use Mozilla Firefox for your Internet browser, you can download the [BetterPrivacy add-on](https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/6623) to automatically delete your Flash cookies every time you close your browser.

If you opt out of these technologies, you will continue to see advertising displayed on the Site, but the advertising may not be targeted to your interests.

Please remember that we do not have access to, or control over, advertisers' or service providers' cookies, and the information practices of third parties are not covered by this privacy policy. For more information on the use of cookies in online advertising, please see the section on Advertising and visit the [NAI's website](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) and the [EDAA's website](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

**7\. Access**

If you choose to share contact information with us, you may update or amend this information by contacting us at [privacy@huffingtonpost.com](mailto:privacy@huffingtonpost.com?subject=Huffington%20Post%20South%20Africa%20Privacy%20Inquiry).

**8\. Confidentiality and security**

We limit access to contact information about you to employees or service providers who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. We also have adopted commercially reasonable technical, physical, and administrative procedures to help protect information about you from loss, misuse, and alteration.

**PLEASE NOTE THAT NO DATA TRANSMISSION OR STORAGE CAN BE GUARANTEED TO BE 100% SECURE. WE WANT YOU TO FEEL CONFIDENT USING THE SITE, BUT WE CANNOT ENSURE OR WARRANT THE SECURITY OF ANY INFORMATION YOU TRANSMIT TO US.**

**Section 8 has important legal consequences for you.   It: **

  * **excludes or limits Huffington Post's legal responsibilities;**
  * **limits or excludes rights and claims you have against Huffington Post; and**
  * **places legal responsibilities and liabilities and risks on you.**

**You know and accept that the internet is not absolutely secure and there is a risk that your personal information will not be secure when transmitting over the internet.   We do not promise that we can keep your personal information completely secure over the internet.**

**You also know and accept that we do not promise the complete security of your personal information.  You will not be able to take action against us if you suffer losses or damages in these circumstances.**

**9\. Visitors from outside the United States**

The Site's offices are located in the United States. If you visit the site from another country, please be aware that information you provide to us or that we obtain as a result of your use of the Site may be processed in and transferred to the United States and will be subject to U.S. law. U.S. privacy and data protection laws may not be equivalent to the laws in your country of residence. **By using the Site or providing us with your information, you consent to the collection, transfer, storage, and processing of information to and in the United States.**

**Section 9 has important legal consequences for you.   It: **

  * **provides your consent to the processing of your personal information outside of your country of residence; and**
  * **places legal responsibilities and liabilities and risks on you.**

**Information may be processed in and transferred to a country which has different privacy and data protection laws.**

**10\. Children**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children. If we learn that we have collected any personal information from a child without parental consent, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as possible. If you believe that we may have collected information from a child, please contact us at [privacy@huffingtonpost.com](mailto:privacy@huffingtonpost.com).

**11\. Changes to the privacy policy**

We may update this privacy policy at any time to reflect changes in our practices and service offerings. If we modify this privacy policy, we will update the "Effective Date." We will notify you of any material changes in the way we treat your information by placing a prominent notice on our site or sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your account.

**12\. Questions and suggestions**

If you have questions about this privacy policy, please contact our privacy team at [privacy@huffingtonpost.com](mailto:privacy@huffingtonpost.com).

**13\. Consumer Protection Act, Protection of Personal Information Act and other laws**

Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this privacy policy, if this privacy policy or any provision in this privacy policy is regulated by or subject to the Consumer Protection Act 68 of 2008, as may be amended from time to time (the "Consumer Protection Act"), the Electronic Communications and Transactions Act 25 of 2002, as may be amended from time to time (the "ECT Act"), the Protection of Personal Information Act 4 of 2013, as may be amended from time to time ("POPI") or other laws,it is not intended that any provision of this privacy policy contravenes any provision of the Consumer Protection Act, ECT Act, POPI or such other laws.  Therefore all provisions of this privacy policy must be treated as being qualified, to the extent necessary, to ensure that the provisions of the Consumer Protection Act, ECT Act, POPI and such other laws are complied with.

No provision of this privacy policy:

  * does or purports to limit or exempt us from any liability (including, without limitation, for any loss directly or indirectly attributable to our gross negligence or willful default or that of any other person acting for or controlled by us) to the extent that the law does not allow such a limitation or exemption;
  * requires you to assume risk or liability for the kind of liability or loss, to the extent that the law does not allow such an assumption of risk or liability; or
  * limits or excludes any warranties or obligations which are implied into this privacy policy by the Consumer Protection Act (to the extent applicable), ECT Act (to the extent applicable), POPI (to the extent applicable), or other applicable laws or which we give under the Consumer Protection Act (to the extent applicable), ECT Act (to the extent applicable), POPI (to the extent applicable), or other applicable laws, to the extent that the law does not allow them to be limited or excluded.

_Effective Date: November 21, 2016_
